Aman Kumar

Associate Staff Engineer

Email: amankumar0511@gmail.com

Contact: 7065488642

Experience summary

I have 5.5 years of experience in the software industry. I have experience as a Software Developer and Data Science Enthusiast. He offers skills in writing software which helps to build great products and helping business succeed with its goals. He is proficient in development of a wide variety of web applications. I have exposure in developing web applications using Python, Python framework (Django, Flask), JavaScript, React JS, Angular JS, and various other bleeding edge technologies. He has a keen interest in data science projects of data mining, data analysis, and machine learning.

Skill set

Programming and scripting languages	Python, JavaScript, HTML, C, C++
Frameworks, tools, and libraries	Django, Django-REST-framework, Flask, Angular JS, React JS, Redux
Servers and platforms	Nginx, supervisor, AWS, Docker, Docker-compose, CI/CD
Databases and BI	Postgres, MySQL, Redis, snowflake
Devices and OS	Linux (Ubuntu), Windows, Mac

Experience:

Organisation: Nagarro soft pvt Ltd. **Duration**: July 2018 to Current

Organisation: Jaarvis tech pvt ltd **Duration:** Jan 2016 to May 2018

Organisation: 91spring board pvt ltd.

Duration: Jan 2015 to Dec 2015 (Internship)

Education

Bachelor of Technology, Computer Science, Shri Mata Vaishno Devi University, Jammu, India



Honors and awards

ACM-ICPC Reginal Level Qualifications

Received three-times best employee award at jaarvistech.

Nominated 4 times in nagarro cheer board programm

Recent projects

Web Application and Data Analysis

Client	Client is in domain energy domain, application built for analyze the plant efficiency and capacity.
Project overview	Project involved the development of a web application using REST services. The application included ETL process of data, after analysis graphical representation on web UI.
Technologies	Python, Postgres, Flask, Ember.js, HTML, CSS, Redis, snowflake
Responsibilities	Involved in: Working on project architect design, database design, and programming Reviewing the code of the other member

Mobile Application and Admin Portal

Client	Client is a mobile carwash company, with waterless concept. It quickly grew into something much more advanced and soon client was involved in a new concept altogether that is carsharing.
Project overview	Project involved the development of a mobile application and admin portal using REST services. The application included integration with payment gateways, social networking platforms, integration with hardware devices, and data caching along with all user related features such as reserve trip using the NFC card reader or mobile app, profile, trip feedback, etc.
Technologies	Python, Django, Django-RESTframework, Postgres, Flask, Angular JS, HTML, CSS, Redis
Responsibilities	Involved in: Working on project architect design, database design, and programming Reviewing the code of the other member

Web Application Development

Client	Client is a mobile carwash company, with waterless concept. It quickly grew into something much more advanced and soon client
	was involved in a new concept altogether that is carsharing.

Project overview	Project involved development of a web application which allowed user to book a waterless car cleaning services, it included different type plan which was subscribed by user on stripe.
Technologies	Python, Django, HTML, CSS, JavaScript
Responsibilities	Involved in: